https://github.com/warpedpuppy

415.902.2952

Web Developer with extensive professional experience in the design, development and maintenance of web sites, games, and applications. Notable experience includes:

- Developed the front-end of a website with traffic of 20 million monthly pageviews.
- Coded in a boiler-room web game development environment, writing strong code guickly.
- Create curriculum and lead webinars on web development for coding academy.
- Mentor for Full-Stack development students.
- Coded and Maintained subscription based ecommerce sites in ReactJS and VueJS.
- Ranked 'Expert' in JavaScript at CoderByte.

Technical Skills:

ReactJS, ReduxJS, VueJS, VueX, NuxtJS, NodeJS, ExpressJS, MongooseJS, AngularJS, Mongo, HTML5, CSS, and more

Professional Experience

Senior Software Engineer, Atlantis Tech, 2021-2022

Coded React front-end for Medical Device Software.

Mentor & Curriculum Developer, CareerFoundry, 2020-Present

- Created >20 videos for use in the CF webdev curriculum.
- Conducted multiple video seminars for groups of students.
- One-on-one mentoring in full-stack programming including ReactJS, NodeJS and AWS.
- Teach JavaScript from fundamentals to advanced.
- Assisted students in app creation, both front-end and back-end.

Mentor, Thinkful.com, 2017-2020

- One-on-one mentoring in web development fundamentals and full-stack programming.
- Teach JavaScript from fundamentals to advanced.
- Assisted students in app creation, both front-end and back-end.

Software Engineer, CleverTech, 2017-2018

- Coded and maintained subscription-based, ecommerce sites.
- Worked with Shopify, Stripe, Mailchimp and Wordpress apis.

Software Engineer, The Dodo, 2016-2017

- Wrote and maintained code for the entire front-end, and part of the back-end of the website.
- Worked directly with the Head of Product to create, edit, and maintain site. Continually polished code to achieve optimized efficiency and operation.
- Collaborated with onshore and offshore development teams.
- Coded and implemented Google Analytics A/B experiments, which required creating alternate versions of the site and managed their application via lazy loaded JavaScript.

Software Engineer, WarpedPuppy LLC, 2013-2016

- Designed, developed and maintained front-ends and back-ends for websites and mobile applications.
 Software Engineer, Starfall Education, 2010-2013
 - Programmed educational games for the website starfall.com and the site's paid section more.starfall.com.
 - Was the only on-staff full-time programmer and had to code extremely complicated games quickly and efficiently.

Education

Various Coding Certificates

AcademyX, San Francisco, CA

Two years of professional trade school focused in HTML, CSS, JavaScript, PHP, MySQL.

Juris Doctor (J.D.)

University of California, Hastings College of the Law

Passed both the California and Connecticut bars. Awarded an HPILF grant.

Bachelor of Arts (B.A.)

University of California, Berkeley

Majored in History, Graduated with Honors.